# Sheharyar Naseer

- sheharyar.me
- hello@sheharyar.me
- +1 (631) 572 7363
- sheharyarn
- sheharyarn
- in sheharyarnaseer

### Skills

**Ruby on Rails** \*\*\*\*

Elixir & Phoenix

Node.js \*\*\*\*

**Android** \*\*\*\*

**DevOps** \*\*\*\*

UX / UI ★★★☆☆

I'm a true full stack developer with years of experience in all layers of web and mobile application development, and working through the complete product development cycle.

Although my best work has always involved Elixir, Ruby, or Android; I possess extensive knowledge in a wide range of technologies and domains, including Javascript (Node, React, Angular), Frontend (Sass, Webpack), laaS (AWS, Heroku, GCP), Java, Redis, SQL & NoSQL, Blockchains and Machine Learning.

# Recent **Projects**

#### Que

A simple and efficient backgound that doesn't have any external has quickly become one of the top Elixir packages in its category (with 250+ stars on Github)

#### **DevFiles**

Development of a high-speed file hosting service built on Rails & MongoDB with custom configurations & optimizations for maximum reliability and uptime

#### **Behavioral Biometrics**

I worked with an industry leadjob processing library in Elixir ing researcher to write a passive authentication system in Java for dependencies (such as Redis). It Android devices that employs SVM based machine learning to authorize users based on their behavior and interaction with the device

#### **BootDroid**

Design and development of a rootbased app for Android power-users, with beautiful UI & animations, that allows them to boot their device in different modes

# Work **Experience**

#### **Technology Consultant**

Various Clients (2010 - Present)

As a freelance consultant, I've worked in many different roles for various companies, providing my expertise in Web and Mobile development, DevOps, distributed systems and fault-tolerance. Most of my work has revolved around Elixir, Ruby, Javascript and Android.

#### Senior Backend Engineer

Elixir Developer at Gustav (2017 - Present)

Gustav is a YC-backed platform to connect employers to staffing agencies. I was responsible for directing the platform's architecture, writing various microservices, and implementing efficient job queues. Most recently, I developed their Asset Pipeline to perform document conversions & optimize user uploaded files.

#### **Full-Stack Engineer**

Node.js Developer at Caremerge (2015)

Caremerge is a Senior Living and Healthcare focused startup based out of Chicago. I designed and developed one of their main medications module in Node.js, Angular, Stylus and Webpack; driving massive sales to the product.

#### Rails & Node.js Developer

Full-Stack Developer at Qwexar (2012 - 2014)

At Qwexar, I worked on a lot of different projects involving analytics and geolocation. One of my main projects was development of an administration dashboard for a startup called Smallnest, where the team could see detailed statistics & data reports, and predict future trends.

See my LinkedIn for complete work history

# **Education**

#### **New York Institute of Technology**

Masters in Computer Science (2017 - Present)

#### **National University of Sciences & Technology**

Bachelors in Electrical Engineering (2010 - 2014)

## **Other**

#### **Open Source**

I'm a very passionate advocate of Open Source technologies and a regular contributor myself. I've published many Elixir libraries, Ruby Gems and NPM packages along with countless scripts that are being used by developers and agencies across the world

#### **StackOverflow**

I contribute a lot of my time answering questions on StackExchange; So much so, that I have a total of **38k reputation** on the network with over 90% from StackOverflow alone. I rank among the top 10 users from Pakistan and in the top 0.1% of all of StackOverflow

#### Speaker & Writer

I share what I learn, so I regularly blog about a wide range of topics regarding software development. I've given a lot of talks in the past on different open source technologies & also have been contracted by DigitalOcean to write technical articles for them

#### **Google Developers Group**

As the technical lead of GDG Lahore, I focus a lot on developer evangelism with my team; organizing events, workshops and developer conferences in Pakistan as a way to empower the emerging developer community here